santacruzbicycles.com 2018-12-13

# Privacy Policy | Santa Cruz Bicycles

**Adopted February 2017**

1.              **Introduction; Agreement.**   At Santa Cruz Bicycles, LLC (“SCB”), your privacy is important to us.  For that reason we want you to understand how we use information you provide to SCB through your use of our websites www.santacruzbicycles.com, www.shop.santacruzbicycles.com, and any other website owned or operated by SCB (collectively, the “Site”).  By accessing any part of the Site and/or materials made available through it on any device, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).  If you do not agree to these terms and conditions, please do not access or use any part of the Site. 

2.              **Personally Identifiable Information.**   In using the Site, you will have the opportunity to provide SCB with personally identifiable information, which may include, without limitation, your name, e-mail address, physical address, IP address, geographic location, telephone number, identification numbers, credit card numbers, billing information, passwords, device identifiers, hardware information, browser type, browser language, number of times you access the Site (and when), information about purchases, information about referring websites, and other information, any or all of which may be necessary or helpful to perform the functions you select on the Site. If you would like to review or change your personally identifiable information in SCB’s possession, please contact SCB using the contact information set forth below. 

3.              **Disclosure.**   SCB will not share your personally identifiable information with anyone without your permission.  Please be aware, however, that your use of the Site constitutes your permission for SCB to use and disclose your personal information in the manner stated in this Privacy Policy.  SCB also reserves the right to disclose any personally identifiable information and other information to third parties if SCB determines in good faith that disclosure is required by any applicable, law, rule, regulation, or governmental order; if it is necessary or advisable to protect SCB’s rights; to investigate, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or related issues; or to protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of SCB, its users, or the public.   

4.              **Use.**   Information you provide to SCB through the Site may be used for any or all of the following purposes: 

(a)           Receiving and processing orders; shipping and returning orders; soliciting customer satisfaction input; auditing internal practices; confirming warranty rights; sharing news about our products, athletes, and events; improving the quality of our products and services; informing customers about recalls and other consumer protection matters; assisting in marketing products and services, including targeted advertising; determining your location, facilitating purchases of our products; and enhancing the technical function and content of the Site. Your information may be retained by SCB for a period we determine is reasonably necessary to accomplish our objectives in collecting the information.  

(b)           Your personally identifiable information may be combined with information received from our affiliates, and it may be transmitted to our affiliates and other third parties for analysis and processing.

(c)            SCB owns the information collected on the Site.  That means that, among other things, if SCB goes through a business transition, such as a merger with or acquisition by another organization, or a sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. 

(d)           If we anticipate the use of your information for any purpose other than those described in this Privacy Policy, we will provide you with an effective opt-in mechanism or in any case obtain your prior consent.  However, public information about you may be freely disclosed.

5.              **Traffic Information.**   Like most websites, the Site automatically gathers certain traffic information and stores it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data.  We may also employ clear GIFs (sometimes known as web beacons or web bugs) to track use of the Site.  Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that are embedded invisibly on web pages or emails.  Information tracked with clear GIFs is anonymous and does not personally identify users.  SCB may use this information to, among other things, ensure levels of service, analyze trends, administer and improve the Site, and gather demographic information about the Site’s user base.  SCB does not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

6.              **Cookies (Updated May 2018).**   The Site uses cookies.  A “cookie” is a small piece of data generated by a website and saved in your internet browser.  It remembers information you provided as well as analytics about how you used the website, and can help to simplify your use of the website.  There are “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies.  Session cookies are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of your browser session.  As compared to a session cookie, a persistent cookie may remain on your browser following your session on the Site.  You can reject cookies by setting your browser to notify you when one is received so you can decide whether to accept or reject it.  Persistent cookies can also be removed by following the directions on your internet browser.  Cookies may be generated from third party websites, and cookies may be used for third-party retargeting and remarketing functions.  Users can view the Site without accepting cookies.  **[See our full cookies policy here](http://www.santacruzbicycles.com/cookies).**

7.              **Google Analytics.**   We use Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google, Inc., which uses cookies to enable analysis of use of the Site, including information about when users view specific pages or take specific actions on the Site.  Google uses this information to compile reports about Site activities and to provide additional services associated with use of the Site and the internet.  Among other things, this allows us to provide you targeted advertising in the future, should we choose to do so.  If you prefer not to receive this type of advertising from us, you can opt out at any time by using the DoubleClick opt-out page or the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.  We will assume you have consented to such use unless you so opt-out or specifically advise otherwise.

8.              **HubSpot.**   We use HubSpot to help analyze and manage user data.  HubSpot is a company based in Cambridge, Massachusetts that develops and markets software products for inbound marketing, which is a technique for drawing customers to products and services via content marketing, social media marketing and search engine optimization.  HubSpot provides us with tools for social media marketing, content management, web analytics, landing pages and search engine optimization. HubSpot may use cookies and other tools to track user data.  Users will have an opportunity to opt-out of HubSpot tracking by using an opt-out feature on the Site. When a user opts-out of HubSpot tracking, HubSpot installs an opt-out cookie valid for two years.  We encourage users to visit the HubSpot website to learn more about the cookies and other tools used by HubSpot and to review HubSpot’s privacy policies.

9.              **Other Websites.**   The Site may contain links or other references to other websites that are not owned or controlled by SCB.  These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect and make use of data received from you.  SCB is not responsible for the content, privacy practices, products or services of such other websites, and SCB disclaims all responsibility and liability associated with such other websites.  This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by the Site.

10.           **California “Do Not Track” Notice.**   Unlike some websites, we do not track your website activities over time and across third party websites.  For that reason we do not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals from a user’s browser.  However, users can opt-out of cookie-based tracking using an opt-out feature on the Site. 

11.           **Security.**   The security of your personal information is important to us.  SCB follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted, both during transmission and once received.  No method of transmission over the Internet or by email is 100% secure.  Similarly, no method of electronic storage is 100% secure.  Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Data may be lost, intercepted, or stolen by unauthorized parties during transmission or storage, and it may be transmitted via open or closed networks in or to other countries without the same level of data protection as your country of residency.  Furthermore, although we take reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy of the information on the website, SCB makes no representations or guarantees to our users with respect to same.  To the maximum extent allowed by applicable law, SCB will not accept liability for direct or indirect losses arising from lost or stolen data (including your personal information) or from any inaccuracies on the Site.  If you require 100% security, do not correspond or transmit data over the Internet or through email.      

12.           **Social Media Plugins.**   The Site may use social media plugins, including plugins for Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Vimeo, Youtube, and others.  When you use those services, web pages you visit may be linked to your account and made known to others, and data may be sent to those service providers.  This means that those third parties may be made aware you have visited the Site and may collect related data.  Those third parties may store portions of your information even if you have not established an account or profile with them.  For information regarding the policies and practices of those third parties, please visit their respective websites.  You may be able to avoid or block third parties from collecting your data by changing your personal settings on the third party’s website or through the use of a suitable add-on for your browser.

13.           **International Transfers.**   We primarily store customer data in the United States.  However, to facilitate our global operations, your personal information may be transmitted and accessed outside the United States.  By using the Site you are consenting to this potential international transfer and access of data.  If you are transferring data to the Site from outside the United States, you assume the risk that U.S. data protection requirements may be insufficient as compared to the requirements of your country.  Users from countries other than the United States should not provide any personal information through the Site unless they consent to the use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy rather than the laws of the user’s home country.

14.           **Credit Card Information.**   If you give us credit card information, we will use it solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payments.  We may use a third party service provider to manage credit card processing.

15.           **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.**   SCB’s Site, products, and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old. Accordingly, we do not knowingly collect or distribute personal information from anyone under the age of 13.

16.           **Ownership.**   The content of the Site, including without limitation text, graphics, or code, is owned or licensed by us.  You may download text and graphics from the Site without modification or alteration and purely for informational, non-commercial purposes.  Subject to the foregoing, you may not use, download, upload, copy, print, display, reproduce, publish, or distribute any information or content on the Site. The trademarks, tradenames, service marks, logos, and slogans on the Site are either ours or are licensed to us from third parties.  Use of any of the foregoing without the prior permission of the owner is strictly prohibited.

17.           **Disclaimer.**   ALL CONTENT ON THE SITE IS PROVIDED AS-IS AND WITHOUT ANY REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED.  TO THE FULLEST EXTENT ALLOWED UNDER APPLICABLE LAW, WE EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM ANY AND ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR PURPOSE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.  WE DO NO WARRANT THAT USE OF THE SITE WILL BE ERROR-FREE, THAT USE OF THE SITE WILL BE FREE FROM INTERRUPTION, OR THAT THE SITE OR THE SERVER(S) THAT MAKE IT AVAILABLE WILL BE FREE FROM BUGS, VIRUSES, AND OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS. WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES AS TO THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, OR RELIABILITY OF INFORMATION AVAILABLE ON THE SITE.  APPLICABLE LAW MAY NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF CERTAIN IMPLIED WARRANTIES, SO THE FOREGOING DISCLAIMERS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.

18.           **Changes.**   SCB reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy, at any time and without notice, simply by posting the modified policy on the Site and without any other notice to you.  Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site, so please review this Privacy Policy frequently. 

19.           **Contact Us.**   If you have any questions concerning this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to review or revise any of your personally identifiable information previously provided to SCB, please contact our Web Administrator using the following information:

Santa Cruz Bicycles, LLC  
Attn:   Web Administrator  
2841 Mission Street  
Santa Cruz, CA 94560

Phone: 831.459.7560   
Fax:     831.459.7561  
Email:  Web@santacruzbicycles.com
